I, Senusret I, was a pharaoh of ancient Egypt during the Middle Ages
The second ruled my people between about 1971 BC and 1926
BC, which makes my reign extend to about 45 years during
The duration of my reign
I am also known as Sisi
Pharaoh is important in the history of ancient Egypt and has a great influence on me
EGYPTIAN Civilization
The Twelfth Dynasty, of which I am the founder, investigated
Great prosperity in ancient Egypt
I considered myself a god, and a sun god, I built many
Temples and huge structures in Egypt, including the Temple
Karnak and Luxor Temple
Under her rule, Egypt achieved political and economic stability.
It witnessed growth in arts, architecture and literature
I led successful military campaigns including the expansion of...
Egypt's influence in Nubia and Canaan
Remaining monuments from my era, including statues
The kidney statues and memorials are a testament to my strength and authority
In terms of social aspects, ancient Egypt was...
The duration of my rule is characterized by the diversity of classes in society and the distribution of power
And wealth
The ruling elite included the pharaoh, the royal family, and officials
Who enjoyed power, wealth and privileges
Social, as for the working class, it consisted of
Peasants and workers who work in agricultural projects
Construction and handicrafts
In addition, there was a higher social class
Enjoys wealth, power, and social status
Featuring nobles, priests and merchants, under my rule Egypt flourished
It witnessed stability and growth
Which made my reign one of the greatest periods in history
Ancient Egyptian civilization