I am King Amenhotep III, Pharaoh of ancient Egypt during
New Bronze Age, part of the Eighteenth Dynasty,
I ruled Egypt for an estimated period of 44 years, starting around 1391
BC until approximately 1345 BC
When Tuthmosis III died, I assumed power and became Pharaoh
In ancient Egypt
I have completed many projects
Worship started by Tuthmosis III, including the Karnak Temple
The Grand Tower in Luxor, and the expansion of the King’s Tunnel in the Western Valley
Near the city of Luxor, religious reforms became famous
And refocusing on the cult of Amun, I have expanded
The Egyptian Empire and its influence in the region
Therefore, we can say that I have completed and completed the work
Which was started by Tuthmosis III during my reign in Egypt
One of my works is to build the city of Luxor and make it the capital
The main city of Egypt, instead of the city of Agouza
Expanding trade and reforming the economy by increasing relations
Trade, expand foreign trade, build a city
The new Akhenaten and its development with temples and palaces
And homes, leading military campaigns to Nubia and Palestine
And Syria to expand Egypt's influence and secure its borders for both sides
Social
My wife, Queen Nefertiti, was given an important role in governance
And decision-making had a special place
She appeared alongside me in many artistic works, which reflects
Its great influence on politics and society in Egypt
In our golden age of art and culture, Egypt has witnessed great progress
In the artistic and cultural field, where the arts have developed and become
Expresses realism and movement better, shows interest
Great for the people, as I appeared next to ordinary people in
Everyday scenes, and finally religious directions focused
And social during my judgment on changing religion and beliefs
Usual in Egypt, the focus of worship was on the sun god Aten,
Which affected the identity and cohesion of society