I am, Hatshepsut, after the death of Senusret III, and despite the challenges
Which faced me as a woman in a righteous age, I decided to take up
Responsibility for completing the mortuary temple of Senusret III, was
This challenge is not only traditional and cultural, but it is
As a challenge to assert ability and leadership in a dominated world
On it men
During the period of rule, I worked hard and diligently to achieve achievements
Many things enhance Egypt's position and maintain its stability
Among the most important of these achievements
Building temples and monumental structures that embody our traditions
Religious and cultural, you expanded and renovated temples
Ancient, and the establishment of new temples such as the Temple of Abu Simbel in
Nubia, and the Karnak Temple in Luxor, also led my government
Successful military campaigns against Egypt's external enemies were achieved
Great victories in Sinai, Palestine and Nubia
These important victories were immortalized in reliefs and statues
Which highlights my courage and leadership in facing military challenges
These achievements were not limited only to the military field.
It also extended to strengthening cultural and commercial relations
With other countries, it sent trade and diplomatic missions
To negotiate important deals and enhance cultural cooperation, which
Contribute to raising Egypt's position globally
Regarding the social aspect, you were a symbol of progress
Women in Egypt, where she assumed the responsibility of ruling as an independent queen
During my rule, I reformed the administrative and judicial system in
Egypt, improving infrastructure to enhance and stabilize the economy
Judgment
In the cultural aspect, support for the arts and sciences was a part
From a vision for Egypt's progress