After the death of Senusret I, I, Senusret III, continued construction
The pyramid and I completed it after he considered me his legal heir
I added some new decorations and elements to the pyramid
The curve, which is considered a wonderful engineering masterpiece
This pyramid highlights the skill of the ancient Egyptians in construction
Its unconventional design is slightly slanted, which gives it beauty
Frida, located in Dahshur, Egypt, is part of the pyramid complex in
Region
My real name is Khawi Hor, but I became known as Snow
After my death, I was known for my great achievements in...
Architecture and construction, and I renovated and expanded temples such as
Karnak and Abu Simbel, and created huge structures such as the pyramid
The curve in Dahshurah, and the Solar Temple
My courage led me into military expansion, leading campaigns
Successful in Sinai, Nubia, and Palestine, and my victories were proven in...
Inscriptions and statues
I was interested in religious matters, and I worshiped Egyptian gods
Ancient, including Ra, the sun god, and Amun, the god Ra
The snake, and I renovated and decorated the temples with these statues
And the inscriptions during the reign of Hakim
Ancient Egypt experienced relative social stability and uniformity
Between different social classes
Documents document the administrative territories that were administered from
By local officials demonstrating organization
Good social and administrative work at that time, in the field of art
And culture, reflecting the statues and temples built during my reign
A rich cultural heritage, and development in arts and architecture
Temples and tombs are decorated with reliefs and statues
Reflect the religious beliefs and cultural traditions of those
Period
Economically and agriculturally, there were systems
Advanced agriculture and interest in agricultural lands and irrigation
With water from the Nile River, economic prosperity indicates
To have active trade with neighboring countries
As for the funerary temple that I built, it is for worship
The gods were honored, especially Amun-Ra, the snake god located in
Abu Simbel area is considered among the tremendous works that
Egypt did it during my rule