I am, Thutmose III, took over Egypt alongside Hatshepsut, and in
During this joint era, the country witnessed several achievements that reflect strength
The progress of governance at that time was among the important achievements
The construction of the Step Pyramid was achieved during his reign
Saqqara, which remains today as a witness to engineering
Amazing, and Jeddah also worked to promote trade
These efforts have seen the discovery of traces of merchant ships,
In the field of construction of memorial monuments
Many monuments were built in ancient Egypt,
Including the famous monument of doors in the Habu Temple at Dendera,
Which is an important part of the country's cultural heritage
I built temples in several locations in Egypt including
Building a temple in Abydos and a temple in the lobby area near
the shortest
These temples are a witness to the religion and culture that...
Diplomatic relations flourished during his reign
It worked hard to develop relations with neighboring countries,
Such as Palestine and Nubia, in order to enhance trade exchange
Political cooperation between countries
Socially, Egyptian society consisted of:
Different classes, including nobles, priests and workers
and the peasants
The ruling class had great power and prestige
High social status and controlled political decisions
and economic in the country
As for religious life, religion played an important role
In people's lives where worship and offering were practiced
Offerings in temples
Amun-Ra and Ra-Horus are considered among the pivotal gods
that time